No one would have believed
in the early years of the 21st century
that our world was being watched
by intelligences greater than our own.
That as men busied themselves
about their various concerns,
they observed and studied
the way a man with a microscope
might scrutinise the creatures
that swarm and multiply
in a drop of water.
With infinite complacency,
men went to and fro about the globe,
confident of our empire over this world.
Yet, across the gulf of space,
intellects vast and cool
and unsympathetic
regarded our planet with envious eyes
and slowly and surely
drew their plans against us.
Tell him to send it over
to the cargo shed.
It's on its way.
Ray.
Ferrier. Whoa.
I need you back in four instead of 12.
I got half of Korea coming in at noon.
No, no, no, I can't.
I'm on a 12-hour blow. Call Tedesco.
Come on. Tedesco can't move
40 containers in an hour.
I got to have somebody
who can do double picks.
I wish I could help you, Sal.
It's the goddamn union regulations.
Come on. I'm in a position here, Ray.
You remember
the union regulations, Sal.
You know what your problem is?
I can think of a couple women
who'd be happy to tell you.
8:30? Did we say that?
We said 8:00.
Hey, this is...
This is one safe-looking new vehicle
you got yourself here, Tim.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
8:00?
We'll be back by 9:30 on Sunday,
depending on the traffic.
There he is.
Get a hug?
Confusing handshake?
Kick in the teeth?
The door's locked.
Still working on those manners?
Hello, Dad.
Hello, Rachel.
Yo, Stan, hurry up.
We got to get to work.
Here, honey. Let me
give you a hand getting that inside.
- The door's locked.
- Sweetheart, let me get it.
- I don't mind. I don't mind.
- Hey, she said she could get it.
- It's heavy.
- She said she could get it.
It's got rollers. Just roll it, roll it.
Yeah, but we can't roll it
up the stairs, can we?
Really, I got it from here, okay?
It's a 302 V8. It's...
It's gonna be out of here next week.
You better get going, you wanna
beat the traffic, don't you think?
You're out of milk.
And everything else.
Yeah.
Could you close the door, please?
Because that's my refrigerator.
I'm gonna go wait outside.
Okay, sweetheart.
I'll see you in a few days.
Bye, Tim.
- I better get this upstairs.
- Let me... Let me get...
- Mom, Mom, Mom.
- Mary Ann...
- Okay, okay.
- Mom, Mom.
A little old to still be sharing,
aren't they?
- I don't hear any complaints.
- No, I do.
Robbie's got a paper on the French
occupation of Algeria due Monday,
which he's yet to begin.
It would be nice if he were done
by the time we got back
so we don't have to keep
him up all night on Sunday.
- I just gotta type it up.
- No.
- You just got to start writing it first.
- I love you, Mom.
I love you.
Listen to your father.
No shoes on the bed.
We'll be at my parents' house
in Boston,
but don't call the house line,
you know, they...
Well, the point is,
I've got my cell phone,
so if anything comes up
or you have any questions, just call me.
Believe it or not, I can handle it.
- I'll leave the phone on.
- Mary Ann.
It's a good look for you.
You think?
Yeah.
Take care of our kids.
Mary Ann,
you got nothing to worry about.
Listen, you tell your mom that
Ray sends his love and kisses.
Right. She'll love that.
The Ukraine,
a country of some 52 million people,
is in almost total blackness tonight
in the wake of a series
of freakish lightning storms
of catastrophic proportion,
which struck the country at
approximately 4:00 a. m. local time.
...EMP, or electromagnetic pulse,
which causes a temporary interruption
of all electrical current within its field.
As in the Ukraine, there are
scattered reports that the EMP here
was followed by seismic activity
on the scale of an earthquake,
measuring 6.5 on the Richter scale.
This...
- Baseball season's over.
- Five minutes. It's not gonna kill you.
There he is.
Boston?
That's how it is?
Is that how it's gonna be?
- Careful with that throw.
- Whatever, Ray.
Mom says you got
a report due on Monday,
so you're gonna work on that
when we're done here.
Yeah, I'm almost finished.
I just got to type it up.
Yeah, bullshit.
Yeah? What do you know, Ray?
Everything. Haven't you heard?
Between me and my brother,
we know everything.
What's the capital of Australia?
That's one my brother knows.
Okay with you if I just laugh the first
500 times you tell that one?
Just do your report.
We don't send you to school
so you can flunk out.
You don't pay for it, Tim does.
That's half what I've got.
You're an asshole. I hate coming here.
That why you act like such a dick?
What?
That's not how you're gonna
get through to him.
- If you want him to listen to you...
- What are you, your mother or mine?
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to sleep.
I work for a living.
- What are we supposed to eat?
- You know, order.
Three and two...
- Electromagnetic storm...
- The storms were tracked...
And I'll have my own little secret.
Good idea, hey, Gary?
- No.
- What do you know?
You're a snail.
What's the matter?
Got a splinter.
Where'd you get it? Come here.
On your porch railing.
Do you need me to... What?
To do what? You want me to...
- You want me to take that out?
- Absolutely not.
Come here. Let me see it. Let me see.
Dad.
- Just look. Don't touch it. Dad.
- Rach.
- I can't. You're moving it around.
- Okay, but don't touch it. Just look at it.
It's gonna get infected.
- No, it won't.
- Yes, it's gonna get infected.
No, it won't.
When it's ready,
my body will just push it out.
- Push it out, huh?
- I read that.
You should get TiVo.
- Tim got it for my room.
- TiVo?
It's awesome.
I can watch all my shows
after homework.
Yeah, I'll just put it on my platinum card.
Robbie? Robbie.
What is that?
Hummus.
- Hummus?
- From the health-food place.
Kept one of their menus
last time we were here.
You said order.
I meant order food.
Where is Robbie?
- He went out.
- Out where?
I don't know.
He just took your car and left.
Who said that? Who's there?
It's the clam burglar.
Steven, look at this.
- What's up?
- Check it out!
You ever see something like that?
Springtime, maybe.
Not this time of year.
Come on, we can see better
from the back yard.
You got to come see this!
- That is so weird.
- What?
The wind is blowing toward the storm.
That is weird.
Hey, watch it!
Rachel, you wanna see something cool?
It's okay.
- I wanna go inside.
- It's okay.
I wanna go inside.
Okay, you go ahead.
That's enough weather for me.
Don't wanna go by myself.
- It's kind of fun, isn't it?
- No.
- Come on, like the Fourth of July.
- No, it's not.
Oh, say can...
It's okay. You're fine.
- It hit right behind our house.
- Yeah, well, it's...
It's not gonna hit there again, okay,
because lightning doesn't strike
twice in the same place.
Shit!
Where's Robbie?
I don't know.
Is Robbie okay?
Are you okay?
Where's the thunder?
Why won't it stop?
Is it over?
Where are you going?
Just... I'm just checking things out.
Just wait. Wait there.
- Are we gonna be okay?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No, I meant, I just...
Rachel, please.
Just stop asking so many questions.
Just wait here.
Turn everything off.
Everything is off.
I can't get one freaking thing to turn on.
You believe this, Ray? Every single car.
Jesus. Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
- The car just stopped, and...
- You're okay?
- Are you okay? You all right?
- The lightning started to hit
about a block away,
over and over again.
- And me and this other guy...
- Where the hell did you go?
- Over on Lincoln Avenue.
- Lincoln Avenue?
- By the church.
- You see it? You saw the lightning?
- Were you near it?
- Yeah, 26 times we counted,
over and over again.
The lightning started to hit.
It opened up this hole or something...
- I don't know.
- Twenty-six times?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- You're okay?
- Yeah.
Good. All right, well,
your sister is in the house,
and I want you to go in that house
and I want you to stay with her, okay?
The next time you take my car with
no driver's licence and no permission,
I call the cops.
You better be there when I get back.
- Yeah.
- Robbie.
Manny, Manny. Manny, what is it, dead?
All of them. Everything. Look at this.
- The starter's fried.
- Lightning hit it?
Not even close.
I thought if I changed it...
- You got any idea what's going on?
- I'm on my way to find out.
Try changing the solenoid.
It's probably fried.
Right, that's what I said.
I told you that. The solenoid.
Hey, they're saying all the lightning
struck down by the church.
What the hell is going on around here?
- Let us through.
- Hey.
- Let us through here.
- Hey, hey.
What up, Ray?
I should've known
you two were behind this.
Hey, God's pissed off
at the neighbourhood, Raymond.
- I'll tell you that much.
- Can you blame him?
- You see it?
- Yeah.
- You got power where you are?
- Nope. Nothing.
It's the cars, though.
You know, that's the thing.
Solar flare.
That's what this guy told me he heard.
- A solar flare?
- Yeah, he says the sun shoots off
- these big blobs of plasma.
- Let me tell you something.
They turn into solar flares.
It's the only thing that can kill
- all the electronic stuff like that.
- Can I tell you something?
The sun does not cause lightning, okay?
Bro, I'm just telling you
what that guy said he heard.
Okay, I understand, but it just
sounds dumb when you're saying that.
I've never seen anything like this before.
That many strikes of lightning
in one spot?
- Is this the only place?
- Come on, put that down.
- You wanna step back, please?
- Step back.
- You're gonna fall in.
- Get back.
Back up, people.
People, back up back there.
Move back. Everybody back up.
Move back.
Is it hot?
No.
- It's freezing.
- What is that?
Hey, move. You feel that?
- I feel that.
- Hey, Bobby, come check this out.
- You feel that?
- Feel that?
- Yeah, I feel that.
- What is it, the subway?
- There's no subway here.
- F train, maybe?
That can't be the water main.
There's nothing else down there.
- Water main doesn't run through here.
- Feel that?
Well, there's something down there
and it's moving.
Everybody, move back.
Whoa. Back it up. Come on.
Let's go.
Come on, folks. Back up. Get back.
Help me out here. Get back.
- Go! Move!
- Everybody, get out of the way!
Everyone, back up!
Everyone, clear the intersection!
Get out of the way! Back up! Back up!
Get out of the way!
- Forget it! Get back!
- Get the hell out of the street!
Move away!
Come on,
we've got to clear this area now!
That's my car!
Go, go.
Get the hell out of here!
Oh, my God!
Come on, people! Let's go!
Come on, back up!
Please! Move back!
Watch it!
Oh, my God.
Ray, no. Stay, man.
Just stay.
- Just stay back here. Stay back!
- Wow.
Come on.
What happened?
What's going on?
Dad, what's the matter?
What's all that stuff all over you?
- Ray.
- What's all this stuff?
Hello?
Ray?
We're leaving this house in 60 seconds.
What? Why?
I have no idea what's going on.
You're responsible for all the food
from the refrigerator and the cupboard,
- and put it in here.
- What's going on?
- Just tell me.
- Just do it.
- Rachel, sweetheart...
- Dad, you're really scaring me.
- ... I need you to get your suitcase...
- Dad.
...the one that you brought,
bring it to me, okay?
Can you just do that for me, darling?
Okay?
I don't think it's a fire.
- See? That looks like smoke to me.
- What's happening?
I can't tell you now.
We've only got about another minute.
Please.
- Just keep it down.
- Ray, I'm standing right beside you.
Can you please answer me?
Just get in the front seat, Robbie.
- Whose car is this?
- Just get in.
Whose car is this?
Hey. Hey, Ray.
You were absolutely right.
That is exact... I had to change the...
Ray? Hey.
Hey, Ray? Ray.
Ray.
What? Come on, open up.
Open the door, come on.
- Open the door, Ray. What are you...
- Get in, Manny.
That's funny.
You got to get out of the car.
- Manny, get in the car.
- It's not my car. It's not your car.
Manny, listen to me, pal.
- Manny, Manny, shut up.
- Kids, Daddy's acting crazy.
You can't do this. Guy's gonna
come back, he's not gonna...
Manny. Manny,
I don't have time to explain.
You're busting my chops.
I got a shop to run.
- Manny, listen to me.
- No, Ray. Get out of the...
Get in, Manny, or you're gonna die.
- What do you mean?
- Okay.
All right, get out of the truck.
I'm not kidding now.
Get out of the car, Ray.
I'm not gonna get in. I'm not getting in.
- Manny, get in with us.
- I'm not gonna get in trouble.
- Look, I'm not fooling around...
- Close the door. Close it.
Ray, bring the car back, Ray.
It's not my car.
Get down! Get down, get down!
Get down!
Is it the terrorists?
- Just get down. Get down! Get down!
- Holy shit!
- Where are we going?
- We got to go.
We got, maybe, like,
the only working car around here.
- I'm not stopping until we're clear of it.
- Clear of what?
- We got to go.
- What the hell is going on?
- Look, you saw, we're under attack!
- By who?
Who is attacking us?
Rachel?
Rachel, you've got to keep it down.
Rachel. Rachel. Shut up, Rachel.
- You're freaking her out!
- Look, I'm driving! Do something!
Okay, put them up, Rach.
Make the arms.
This space right here, this is yours.
This belongs to you, right?
- Yes.
- You're safe in your space.
- I'm safe in my space.
Nothing can happen to you
in your space.
- Okay.
- I'm really scared.
I'm gonna go to the front seat,
I'm gonna talk to Dad.
- No.
- I'll be two feet away. Okay?
- Okay.
- Will you hold my hand?
- Yes.
- Are you gonna be okay?
I wanna know everything you know.
This...
This thing, this machine,
it crawled out of the ground,
started torching everything.
It was killing everybody.
What is it? Is it terrorists?
No, this came from someplace else.
- What do you mean, like Europe?
- No, Robbie, not like Europe!
That machine, it was already buried.
Maybe it...
It came down in the lightning storm.
- They came down in the lightning storm.
- What do you mean "came down"?
- You just said it was buried.
- No, the machine I'm talking about
was buried, but what came down
in the lightning storm,
what operates it, that's the... You know.
- The what?
- That's the...
Why aren't there any helicopters
or airplanes?
- It's the what?
- Hey, Rach. How you doing there, girl?
- How is she doing?
- How you doing?
- Fine.
- She's good.
Yeah? Good.
What was that thing you did with her?
Works sometimes.
She gets claustrophobic.
Yeah? Hey, Rachel? Hey.
- I want Mom.
- Yeah, I know. You feel better?
- Yeah? Tell me about it, you know?
- Take me to Mom's.
- Listen, what I need you to do is,
is I just need you to hold it together
for me, okay?
I want Mom!
When you start screaming like that,
you know, I can't really drive...
- Take me to Mom's!
- I know that.
That's where we're going right now.
- Rachel...
- Take me to Mom's!
I know!
Hurry up, Dad. Come on.
Robbie, get the door.
Mom!
- Mom!
Mom? Tim?
- Mom?
- Tim?
Tim?
Mom?
They're gone.
Is she dead?
She's not dead. All right?
She's just not here, okay?
- They were never here.
- How do you know?
Because they're on their way to Boston.
And so they just
kept on going up to Boston.
They're probably
at your grandma's house by now.
I'm gonna call her.
How come the lights are on here
and not at your place?
Because nothing bad happened here.
Okay?
So we're safe here. All right?
Okay, Rachel? This is your area.
- Okay, you are safe...
- Dad, that's not how it goes.
Okay. Well, are you hungry?
I'll get you some food.
I'm gonna feed you.
Get something to eat.
- What do we have? We have...
- Busy signal.
- It's one of the fast ones.
- What is this? Ketchup, mustard...
- You think all the circuits are down?
- Tabasco, barbecue sauce.
You know, this is really good, Robbie.
Vinaigrette. I said pack food.
- What the hell is this?
- That's all that was in your kitchen.
Okay. That's all right.
All right. Okay.
Food. Bread.
Okay. We're gonna have...
Let's get some sandwiches.
Wanna see me deal?
Wanna see me deal? Here we go.
There's two for you.
There's two for Robbie.
There's two for me, one for the house.
Okay.
Maybe after we eat something,
I'll go down and show you guys...
Teach you how to play some poker?
A little five-card stud?
- Maybe a little blackjack.
- I'm allergic to peanut butter.
Since when?
Birth.
Okay, well, here.
You can eat the bread. Okay?
I'm not hungry.
Okay, well,
Robbie and I are gonna be eating
peanut butter sandwiches.
- Want jelly on this sandwich?
- I'm not hungry either.
You're not hungry either? Okay.
Okay, that's fine.
Everybody just relax, okay?
Because we're here now.
We're safe, and we're gonna stay.
And in the morning,
your mom and Tim are gonna be here.
And everything's gonna be fine.
Okay?
Okay.
If everything's fine, why do we
have to sleep in the basement?
- We've got perfectly good beds.
- Hey, it's like a slumber party.
What are you afraid
is gonna happen to us?
Nice basement.
I wanna sleep in my bed.
I've got back problems.
Okay. Well...
You know on the weather channel
when there's a tornado,
and they tell you to go down
to the basement for safety? It's like that.
- There's gonna be tornadoes?
- Okay, Rachel.
Hey, no more talking, okay?
- Could you be a little nicer to me?
- No more talking.
God.
- Wanna stay here?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Good night. Love you.
Love you, Rach.
Is the lightning back?
No, this is something else.
- What's that sound?
- I've never heard that before!
Is it them? Is it them?
We got to go.
Where do we go?
Robbie, this is your house.
No, no, no, wait!
Are we still alive?
Down here.
Were you on this plane?
Are you... Are you a passenger?
How you doing?
Wanna help me open this?
Are you a passenger?
He's deaf.
The shell went off right beside him.
Camera on his shoulder saved his life.
You hear that, Max?
Your stupid camera
saved your stupid life.
Where were you?
Out there in the Pine Barrens.
We were attached to
a National Guard unit.
The 83rd Mechanised.
They moved on one of those things
around midnight.
They've got some kind of shield
around them.
You can't see it, but everything
we fire at them detonates too early,
before we can get close enough
to cause any damage.
When they flash that thing,
everything lights up like Hiroshima.
There's more than one?
You got to be kidding me, right?
We were feeding New York,
but New York went dark.
So we patched over to DC,
they went down.
LA, Chicago, uplinked to London.
Even called the affiliates
to try to get them to catch the feed,
but nobody answers.
It's the same everywhere.
Once the Tripods start to move,
no more news comes out of that area.
My God.
You ain't seen nothing yet.
I saw that storm.
I was right in the middle of one of those.
Well, you didn't see it like this.
Those machines come up
from under the ground, right?
So that means they must've been
buried here a long time ago.
So who's driving the goddamn things?
Watch the lightning.
Watch it.
Keep watching the lightning.
What is that?
That is them.
They come down in capsules,
riding the lightning into the ground,
into the machines, right?
You hear that?
We're getting the hell out of here.
Get in, get in, get in, get in.
Hey, were you on that plane?
That's too bad.
It would've been a really great story.
Look at me. Look at me.
You keep your eyes only on me,
understand?
- Okay.
- Don't look down. Don't look around me.
I'm taking you to the car.
You're gonna want to look around.
But you're not going to.
- Are you?
- No.
You're doing good. You're doing good.
Keep your eyes on me.
I'm going right to Boston.
- We're gonna see your mom.
- I'm not gonna look, Dad.
That's a girl. That's my girl. Now listen.
- I want you to close your eyes, okay?
- Okay.
Got them closed? There you go.
- Keep them closed for me.
- Okay.
Robbie, get in.
- Robbie, get in!
- Why are you yelling?
It's okay.
Get in.
- Why the hell aren't we on the turnpike?
- Because I don't want everybody
to see that we've got a working car.
We'll stay along the Hudson
till we find an open bridge or ferry,
then we're gonna cross the Hudson.
We'll take the back roads across
Connecticut, all the way to Boston.
- Where is everybody?
- I don't know, running, hiding.
- Hiding in their basements.
- If we had any balls, we'd go back there
- and find one of those things and kill it.
- Right. Yeah, good.
Why don't you just let me
make the big decisions, okay?
Which would be when? Never, Ray?
- Never's about your speed.
- Stop it, Robbie.
Enough of the "Ray" shit. All right?
- It's "Dad," "sir"...
- Don't fight!
...or if you want, "Mr. Ferrier. "
That sounds a little weird to me,
but you decide.
- Dad?
- Yes, Rachel.
I've got to go to the bathroom.
Really?
- I got to go.
- Not so fast, not so fast, all right?
There's two things
we got to watch out for.
And the second is people
who might want our car.
- There's nobody around.
- Yeah. I got to go.
All right. Rachel?
Rachel, it's good right there.
I'm not going in front of you guys.
All right,
then just go where I can see you.
Are you crazy?
- Don't look!
- Well, I'm not gonna look.
- Just stay in sight!
- That's looking!
Okay, well, listen, every time
you guys don't listen to me,
I'm telling your mother, okay?
I'm making a list.
Making a list.
- I told you to stay where I could see you.
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
Stop! Don't go!
Wait! Stop! Let me on!
Let me on! Give me a hand!
Wait! Stop!
- Stop! Give me a hand!
- Hey, watch it, kid,
you're gonna get yourself run over!
- Give me a hand! You have room!
- Robbie!
- Robbie, you wanna go in that direction?
- Stop! Stop! Wait!
There's nothing living
in that direction, Robbie.
What do you care?
You never gave a shit before.
- You never gave a shit!
- Okay, hard-ass,
what's your plan, huh?
You're in charge now!
You tell me what we're doing.
What do we do?
We catch up with these soldiers!
Hook up with whoever else isn't dead,
and we get back at them.
We get back at them.
That's what we do.
Now let's try one that doesn't involve
your 10-year-old sister joining the Army.
- You have anything like that?
- Why don't you just tell us the truth?
- Wanna try something like that?
- You have no idea which way to go.
- You have anything like that?
- You wanna come off all wise and shit!
You only chose Boston
because you hoped Mom was there.
And if she's there,
you can dump us on her.
You can dump us on her, and then
you'll only have to care about yourself,
which is exactly the way you like it.
Robbie! Where are you trying to go?
What are you trying to do?
Who's gonna take care of me if you go?
This is a test of
the Emergency Alert System.
If this had been an actual emergency,
official messages
from federal, state or local authorities
would have followed the alert tone.
This concludes the test
of the Emergency Alert...
I'll close my eyes.
Why don't you drive for a bit?
I don't have a licence.
Since when has that stopped you?
Ray.
Ray! Dad!
You think you could...
Do you think you could...
Don't stop.
Don't take your foot off. Okay?
I got it, but keep your foot on.
Okay, I got it. I got it.
- Where is everybody going?
- I don't know, Rach.
But we do, right?
Yeah, we do.
Why did he do that?
- Why is he doing that?
- He wants a ride, Rach.
- Everybody just wants a ride.
- Can we give him one?
Sit back and put on your seat belt.
Robbie, put on your seat belt.
Put on your seat belt, Rachel.
- Be careful.
- How'd you fix this?
- How'd you fix the car?
- Please!
I'm sorry, I can't. I can't.
Please, get away from the car.
Hey! Stop the car.
- Stop the car!
- Get off the car!
You could carry 20 people in there!
- Stop the car!
- Get off the car!
Stop the car!
Hold on.
- Wait, wait.
- Look out. Look out.
Look out! Hold on!
Are you okay?
Stop!
- Ray!
- Robbie!
No, wait! Wait!
No! No, just wait! Okay! Wait! Stop!
- Just stop!
- Daddy!
Rachel!
Get out of there!
Robbie!
Daddy!
- Ray!
- Get in the car!
- Help!
- Rachel! Get out of the car!
Rachel, get... Get out of the car.
- Get out!
- Daddy!
- Take it easy!
- Get off the car! Get off the car!
Get off! Get off the car. Move! Move!
Where's my son?
You don't need that, man.
Put the gun down.
- Where's my son? Robbie!
- Cool down, man.
- Put the gun down, man.
- Robbie!
Put it down.
Dad!
Okay, man, now, listen.
- Put down the gun. I'm taking the car.
- My daughter's in the car.
- Please. All I want...
- Put down the goddamn gun!
- All I want is my daughter.
- I'm taking the car, man.
- Please, I just want my daughter.
Please, let me...
Let me just take my daughter. Can I...
- All I want is my daughter.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Go ahead, man. Take her.
- Take my daughter?
Take her. Yeah. Yeah.
Robbie.
Take me with you.
Have you seen this girl?
This is my daughter.
He needs his medicine.
We've got it the worst,
that's what I heard.
The US, mostly.
South America and Asia, some.
There's nothing going on in Europe.
Europe got the worst of it,
that's what everybody's saying.
- Completely wiped out some of it.
- I don't give a shit who it is.
I got up close to one of those things
in Stanfordville.
If they're all over the place, we're dead.
- Looks like the power's still on here.
- Yeah.
Yeah, power's still on.
Because nothing bad's come up
from the ground.
- Hold on. Hold on, move back.
- Watch out there, lady.
I said, move back.
Unless you are O-positive
and Rh-negative, thank you very much,
but we already have
more blood than we can use.
Again, if you are O-positive,
Rh-negative, identify yourselves.
If you are not, thank you very much.
We already have more blood
than we can use for the transfusions.
Let's go, folks.
This way. This way. Keep it moving.
Keep it moving. This way.
Let's go, folks. Keep it moving.
Please move forward calmly.
The boat can make more than one trip.
Take your time. Don't rush.
Ray! Ray! Ray!
- Sheryl?
- Yeah. Hey.
Oh, my gosh, is this your...
- Are these your kids?
- This is Rachel.
Hi, I'm Sheryl. How are you?
This is my daughter, Nora.
- Nora. I've heard about you, Nora.
- Hi.
- This is my son, Robbie.
- Just like Dad.
- It's good to see you as well.
- Trees are funny.
We're gonna move a few cars out
of the way to make some more space.
You're gonna have to give us
a few minutes.
But don't worry,
there'll be plenty of room for everybody.
- We got sick people here. Let us on.
- Let us on, for Christ's sake.
Cast off. Get that ramp up.
Cast off now. Get that ramp up.
Cast off.
No more people. No more people.
We're taking the ramp up.
Stay close. Stay close.
Everybody, stop. Everybody, stop.
- Wait, wait, wait. Just...
- Back up. Back up.
- There's room.
- Just stay back.
There's no more room.
Just listen to me. There's three of us.
- Five. There's only five of us.
- There's no more room.
Okay, man, just don't push me.
- Sir, there's no more room.
- There is plenty of room.
- There's room for hundreds more.
- Sir...
- Everybody, wait.
- Hold on.
- You just stay with me.
- Okay.
Grab my jacket.
Everybody, back up.
Back up.
I got you, Ferrier.
- Oh, Jesus.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Come on. Come.
- Okay. Jesus. Oh, my God.
- Come on. Come on.
Watch out.
Come on.
- Move. Move. Move.
- Ray.
Ray!
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- Move it! Get out of here!
Go. I can go with him.
Sheryl?
- Stay back.
- Go with them. Go.
- Ray.
- Sheryl?
- Everybody...
- There's room on the boat.
- Let us through, God damn it.
- There's still room on the boat.
- She's a child.
- Robbie.
- There's room on the...
There's still room on the boat.
There's room on the boat.
Up there!
- Robbie.
- Just stay with me.
Stay with me, Robbie.
Robbie!
- Robbie. Robbie.
- Robbie.
Robbie!
- Come on.
Here. Grab my hand.
Here. Hold on.
I got you. Hold on.
Take my hand.
Take it. Take my hand.
Here!
Oh, my God.
Robbie!
Swim. Swim this way.
- Robbie!
- Help me. Help me with her.
- Here, Rach.
Don't stop. Don't stop.
Don't stop.
Oh, my God.
Robbie, slow down.
- Robbie.
- We gotta stay together, Robbie.
Robbie?
Stay together.
Robbie!
Get back here!
No, Robbie! Come back!
Robbie.
Don't move. Don't move.
Now, for God's sake, stay right here.
I'm coming right back.
- Robbie!
- Stop those people.
- Turn around. Turn around.
- Robbie.
Robbie.
What the hell?
Why are you doing this?
Pull back.
Five hundred metres to my 10 o'clock.
Jekyll, no effect on target. No effect.
Roger. No effect.
Our mission, Lieutenant,
is to delay their advance
till those refugees get to safety.
Now, keep firing.
You've gotta listen. Turn around!
I want you to listen to me.
Listen to me.
Go back down the hill.
All of you, just turn around.
- Don't do this. I know you wanna fight.
- I wanna be here.
- I need to see this.
- I know it seems like you have to,
- but you don't. You don't.
- Please, let me go.
Okay. Wait, wait, wait.
What are you doing here all by yourself?
Look, sweetie,
you gotta come with us, please.
No. My dad's getting my brother.
I have to stay here.
- You can't stay here.
- We gotta go.
- I'm not gonna leave her alone.
- Leave.
I'm not letting you do this.
You can hate me.
- You can hate me. But I love you.
- Let me go. Please.
- Let me go. Dad.
- I'm not letting you do this.
I can't. No. Please. Please don't pull me.
It's gonna be okay. You need
to come with us. It is not safe...
Please, let me stay here. Please.
I can't go with you.
- My dad's right there.
- Please, come.
- Please, my dad's right there.
- Will you just listen to me?
I need to be here. I want to see this.
Wait. Wait. Just stay for Rachel.
Stay for your sister.
Please, let me go.
You need to let me go.
All right. Okay. All right.
You're coming with us.
- We gotta go! Now!
- Dad.
- We're going now.
- No, no, you don't understand.
Dad!
Let me go! Dad!
Guide on. Guide on. Black Six.
Attack. Attack. Attack.
Stop.
- That's my dad.
- I'm her father. I'm her father.
- We're so sorry.
- We thought she was alone.
- She was standing by the tree...
- She's fine. Let's go! Let's go!
Robbie.
Robbie!
Over here.
Over here!
Hurry.
Are you all right?
Hey.
What about you, huh?
There you go.
Is that comfortable?
I need you to close your eyes
now, okay?
You need some sleep.
Dad?
He's gonna meet us.
Hey. Robbie's gonna meet us, Rach.
In Boston, at your grandma's.
What do you think
Mom's doing right this minute?
Mom?
Boston. She's waiting.
And I know she's not sleeping,
because she is so worried about you.
And she's in Grandma's kitchen,
and she's...
She's making that awful tea she makes.
And they're all just...
They're all just counting the minutes
until they see you again.
What is this? What is this?
- I won.
- You won?
The walk, trot and canter.
Third place.
Sing me Lullaby and Goodnight.
I don't know that one.
Sing me Hushabye Mountain.
I'm sorry, Rach. I don't...
I don't know that one either.
I'm not bragging, babe
So don't put me down
'Cause I got the fastest
Set of wheels in town
Something comes up to me
They don't even try
'Cause if I had a set of wings
Man, you know she could fly
She's my little deuce coupe
You don't know what I got
Just my little deuce coupe
Peach schnapps.
Disgusting, I know it.
Found a whole case of this shit.
Thank you.
I'm sorry about your son.
We got separated. He's...
He's gonna meet us in Boston.
Did you...
Did you lose anybody?
All of them.
Harlan Ogilvy.
Ray Ferrier.
I got water.
Food enough for weeks.
You're welcome to stay. Both of you.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna get some sleep.
Those machines,
those Tripods they got,
they buried them.
Right under our feet.
Since before there...
There were even people here.
They've been planning this
for a million years.
- We're beat to shit.
- Please.
- My daughter...
- Think about it.
They defeated the greatest power
in the world in a couple days.
Walked right over us.
And these are only the first.
They'll keep coming.
This is not a war
any more than there's
a war between men and maggots.
This is an extermination.
You afraid?
Of course I am.
I been around death plenty.
I drive an ambulance in the city...
Drove an ambulance in the city.
That's all over now, huh?
You know the people that make it, Ray?
The ones that don't flatline
before the hospital?
It's the ones that keep their eyes open.
That keep looking at you. Keep thinking.
They're the ones that survive.
We can't lose our heads, Ray.
Running.
That's what'll kill you.
And I'm dead set on living.
Dead set on living...
Thank you for taking us in.
Not gonna be exterminated.
It's okay. Come on.
I wanna show you something.
We're gonna fight them, Ray.
They got to have a weakness.
Come. Take a look.
Somehow they killed a few of these
things in Osaka. That's what I heard.
You telling me the Japanese
can figure it out, but we can't?
We can do this, Ray.
We can do it. We can get them.
We can figure it out.
Stay right there.
I have a daughter.
Why did you bring us here?
To fight them together, Ray.
Now we'll be the ones coming up
from underground.
When the time is right,
take them by surprise,
the way they took us.
Take them by surprise.
We're right under their feet, Ray.
Right here. Under their feet.
You miss your mommy?
I had a little girl.
Nearly your age.
You know, if anything happens
to your daddy, I'll take care of you.
Rachel.
You don't have anything to say to her.
Do you understand?
If you wanna talk to somebody,
if you wanna ask a question,
you ask me.
What exactly is your plan, Ray?
I know what I'm gonna do.
How about you?
You gonna sit here?
Wait for them to come get you?
Is that your plan?
Maybe you want to get caught.
Couple days hiding in a basement
too much for you, I bet.
You'll probably turn yourself right in.
Listen.
- It stopped.
- Maybe you'll be okay.
Maybe you'll get lucky,
and they'll train you as their pet.
You know, feed you,
train you how to do tricks.
Will you shut up and listen?
No.
Give me that.
You and me,
I don't think we're on the same page.
Ray. Ray.
Ray. Ray. Ray!
Ray!
Keep your voice down. Quiet!
Not my blood. Not my blood.
Not my blood.
Not my...
Not
my...
Not my blood.
- Not my blood.
- Stop it.
You gotta be quiet.
- You want them to hear you?
- They drink us.
- Please, they'll hear you.
Then they spray us, like fertiliser.
You gotta be quiet.
- Drink us, and...
- They're gonna come back down here.
Then they spit us out all over
the goddamn red weeds.
Do you understand
what I'm gonna have to do?
I can't let my daughter die
because of you.
This tunnel will get us to the city.
We'll have our own tunnels there.
Ready-made.
- Stop it.
- Subway. See what I'm saying?
- We can hide a whole army down there.
- Stop it.
We'll go underground.
Sneak attacks at night.
Stop. Stop. You stop it!
We're the resistance, Ray.
They can't occupy this country.
Occupations always fail.
History's taught us that
a thousand times.
This is our land.
We eat it, we breathe it,
only we can live on it.
They can't survive here, Ray.
They weren't built for it.
- They're gonna kill you, brother, not me!
- What are you doing?
- Not my blood!
- What are you doing, Dad?
Whatever you hear, don't take this off.
- Dad?
- Rach?
- What was that song?
- That lullaby that I didn't know?
- Not my blood!
- Hushabye Mountain?
- Yeah, sing it.
- They can take you!
- Please, Rach, sing it.
They can take you!
A gentle breeze
- Your daughter! Not me!
- Don't stop.
On Hushabye Mountain
- They're gonna kill you!
- That's my girl.
Softly blows over Lullaby Bay
Forget it! Tunnel!
It fills the sails
Of boats that are waiting
Waiting to sail your worries away
So close your eyes
On Hushabye Mountain
Wave goodbye to cares of the day
And watch your boat
From Hushabye Mountain
Sail far away
From Lullaby Bay
Rachel?
Oh, my God, no.
Rachel? Rachel?
Rachel? Make some noise, baby.
Rachel?
Rachel? Just talk to me, baby. Come on.
Rachel!
No, no, no! No!
Hey!
Help!
What is happening?
Rachel!
Rachel.
Rachel. Rachel.
Dad.
No! No!
- Pull me! Pull me!
- No!
Pull! Pull!
- Pull me.
- Come on, pull!
- Dad!
- One, two, three...
- We got him!
- We got you.
Keep pulling!
Everybody down!
Keep it moving, folks.
Keep going, sir. Keep moving.
- Oh, God.
- I don't know what's going on.
Hold Grandma's hand.
Let's go, folks. Keep moving forward.
Put that down.
Right this way, ma'am.
Right this way. Thank you.
To the left, there, ma'am,
just to your left. Thank you.
What happened to it?
It's dying.
Keep moving forward.
Keep moving. It's all right.
You can pass on through. Move along.
- What happened here?
- I don't know.
Something's happening to them.
Please, keep moving.
- Let's go, move out.
- Let's go, people.
- Something's happening to them.
- Go. Go, just keep moving, sir.
Let's go, sir. Let's go.
Do not stop. Keep moving. Keep moving.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
What's happened here?
- Did you guys take it down?
- No, sir, it was behaving erratically,
walking in circles, then it went down
on its own about an hour ago.
Now, please, let's go. Let's go.
Keep moving. Come on. Don't stop.
Do not stop! Let's go! Thank you!
How is it dead all by itself?
- Rachel, I'm not sure.
- Coming through.
Coming through. Make a hole.
Coming through.
Calm down.
Calm down and get in the tunnel.
Everybody, calm down.
Get in the tunnel.
Everybody, on the other side
of the tracks!
Look at the birds!
I can't hear you!
Look at the goddamn birds!
- No shield!
- I can't hear!
No shield!
The Javelin's the key!
Load the Gustav!
It's gonna be a tough kill!
Let's go!
It's safer in here.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Bring out the Javelin!
Clear! Go from behind! Clear!
- Let me know when you're tracking!
- Tracking!
- You got a lock?
- I got a lock!
Fire the Javelin!
- Fire the Javelin!
Fire!
It's okay.
I love you.
- It's okay. You're gonna be okay.
- Let's go!
Keep those civilians out of there.
Back. Stay back!
Come on, folks, back up!
Come on, guys, get on the line.
Get up there now.
- Stay back. Stay right here, huh?
- Hold on right there.
- It's opening.
- It's opening. Keep them back.
Clear!
No, keep them back. Keep them back.
Come on, stay back.
Mom!
Thank you.
- Robbie?
Hi, Dad.
From the moment the invaders arrived,
breathed our air, ate and drank,
they were doomed.
They were undone, destroyed,
after all of man's weapons
and devices had failed,
by the tiniest creatures that God
in his wisdom put upon this Earth.
By the toll of a billion deaths,
man had earned his immunity,
his right to survive among
this planet's infinite organisms.
And that right is ours
against all challenges,
for neither do men live, nor die, in vain.